Theo Erikson

Email: theohe1001@gmail.com
Website: theohe1001@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/theoerikson1001</u> Phone: 605-659-0635

Portland ME, 04101

Personal Statement

I am an agile engineer ready to gain any experience I am offered. My skills in 3D design, data analysis and visualization, systems creation, and problem solving are well practiced. A smile-rich style of interpersonal communication allows me to cultivate meaningful and productive relationships with my colleagues.

Experience

Process Engineer I, IDEXX Laboratories, Westbrook | 2023-Present

- Created a flow cell recovery process which saved over \$400,000 over 3 months.
- Applied CAD expertise to ready parts for high volume manufacturing.
- Assists with maintenance and creation of manufacturing fixtures.

Founder and President, Happy Home Computers, Maine | 2022-Present

- Refurbishes, distributes, and services computers free of charge for underserved communities.
- Coordinates and executes donations with other volunteers (150+ since 2022).
- Collaborates with other Maine based non-profits to maximize outreach.

Junior Technical Manager, VEMI Lab, University of Maine | 2021-2023

- Contributed to the design and construction of the world's first 360° immersive fully autonomous vehicle ride simulator.
- Mentored undergraduate researchers and developers.
- Conducted tours for industry, academics, donors, and potential students.
- Part of a winning team for the 2021 USDOT Inclusive Design Challenge.

Hardware Analyst, VEMI Lab | 2019-2023

- Designed, fabricated, and assembled interdisciplinary research fixtures.
- Created and proctored experiments studying human-computer interaction.
- Designed and implemented a new organization system for the lab's digital files and hardware.
- Operated and maintained VEMI's makerspace, including 3D printers, a soldering station, and a laser cutter.

Accomplishments

- Three peer-reviewed articles published.
- Maine research and education speaker (7 events, 2019-2023).
- Passed the Fundamentals of Engineering exam.
- Advanced SolidWorks part modeling, tolerance stack, and GD&T training (ASMR Y14.5 Standard).

Skills

SolidWorks | Blender | GD&T | Excel | JMP | MATLAB | Mathcad | Python | Arduino | Unity 3D | HTML | Circuit Design Lean Manufacturing | Communication | Technical Writing | Project Documentation | Prioritization | Agile Learning

Education

University of Maine, BS Mechanical Engineering, Mathematics Minor, Summa Cum Laude, Top Scholar, GPA: 3.85 | 2019-2023